ARPITH M

Mysore 9900619836 appuarpith1995@gmail.com

Versatile Cloud/DevOps Engineer with 6.5 years of experience. To be associated with progressive organization which provides me the best platform that utilizes my skills and abilities to the fullest for development of the self and the firm.

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2021 - PRESENT

INFRA DEVELOPER, COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY AND SERVICES

Client Info: Capital One Bank UK

Roles

As a Infra Developer I was involved in migration of several application from on-prem to AWS using gear files/terraform which is IaC tool.

Responsibilities

- We are currently migrating ETL tool called Abinitio application from on-prem to aws using serverless architecture.
- Experience in AWS cli.
- Previous projects involve the migration of Apache Webservers from On prem to AWS.
- Onboarding new application ASV in SNOW.
- Infrastructure creation using Bogie file (oneCloud CLI) which acts like a wrapper to Terraform in environments like Dev, SIT and Prod.
- Creating and updating policies to infrastructure using jenkins pipeline.
- creating security group updates using terraform (onecloud CLI).
- AMI refreshes/Rehydrations.
- Configuring required dashboards in New Relic and Datadog monitoring.
- Identifying fixes for vulnerability findings from Security team.
- Support for application testing.
- Configured Logzio for logs monitoring.
- Designing low level architecture.

MAY 2021 - OCT 2021

DEVOPS ENGINEER, TEST YANTRA PVT LTD

Roles

As a DevOps engineer have created POCs for two financial clients of TestYantra **Responsibilities**

- I implemented Jenkins Pipeline for Continous Integration and Continous Deployment.
- Created Dockefiles to create custom images for deploying the applications.
- Integrated Sonarqube and Jfrog for analysis and artifactory purpose

MAR 2018 - MAY 2021

TECHNICAL CONSULTANT, SAMARTHA INFOSOLUTIONS PVT LTD

Roles

As a Technical consultant, I was creating Infrastructure's in AWS in Dev and SIT environments and doing day to day activities.

Responsibilities

- Responsible for architecting, designing, implementing and supporting of cloud-based infrastructure and its solutions.
- Proficient in AWS services like VPC, EC2, S3, ELB, Autoscaling Groups (ASG), EBS, RDS, IAM, CloudFormation, Route 53, CloudWatch, CloudFront, CloudTrail.
- Experienced in creating multiple VPC's and public, private subnets as per requirement and distributed them as groups into various availability zones of the VPC.
- Created NAT gateways and instances to allow communication from the private instances to the internet through bastion hosts.
- Used security groups, network ACL's, internet gateways and route tables to ensure a secure zone for organization in AWS public cloud.
- Created and configured elastic load balancers and auto scaling groups to distribute the traffic and to have a cost efficient, fault tolerant and highly available environment.
- Implemented CI/CD configuration with Jenkins and docker containers.
- Knowledge in deploy Kubernetes.
- Responsible for performing tasks like Branching and Release Activities on Version Control Tools like GIT.
- Created S3 buckets in the AWS environment to store files, sometimes which are required to serve static content for a web application.
- Configured S3 buckets with various life cycle policies to archive the infrequently accessed data to storage classes based on requirement.
- Possess good knowledge in creating and launching EC2 instances using AMI's of Linux, Ubuntu, RHEL, and Windows
- Used IAM for creating roles, users, groups and implemented MFA to provide additional security to AWS account and its resources.
- Written cloud formation templates in json to create custom VPC, subnets, NAT to ensure successful deployment of web applications.

EDUCATION

AUG 2013-2017

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING, VIDYA VIKAS ENGINEERING COLLEGE

Percentage: 67

JUNE 2011-2013

PRE UNIVERSITY COLLEGE, GOPALSWAMI COLLEGE

Percentage: 88

SKILLS

- AWS
- Terraform
- Docker
- Shell Scripting
- Python
- Ansible
- Logzio
- Datadog, New Relic
- Confluence documentation
- Jenkins

ACTIVITIES

Amazon certified in **AWS Solution Architect Associate**Udemy certified **in Docker Certified Associate**